<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on The Practice Room</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on The Practice Room</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Concise Guide to a Quality Percussion Practice Routine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/percussion_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/percussion_practice/</guid>
      <description>By EJ Barasona&#xA;So there I was, eating my Frankie’s Pizza when suddenly I was approached by none other than Andrew McAllister, asking me to write a blog post about how to practice percussion. This got me thinking about whether there really is an ideal practice routine. The answer is that one person’s strategy that gives them excellent progress may not be the perfect strategy for someone else in a different situation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practicing Music Without An Instrument</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/practicing_without_an_instrument/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 14:17:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/practicing_without_an_instrument/</guid>
      <description>Music is loud.&#xA;Instruments are bulky.&#xA;Traveling with instruments is difficult.&#xA;These are all reasons why musicians like you and me don&amp;rsquo;t practice when they&amp;rsquo;re traveling, late at night, or without access to their instrument. But, the best musicians in the world are becoming better, even when they don&amp;rsquo;t have their instrument at their fingertips. In this article, we will go through 6 different methods on how to improve as a musician without your instrument.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Jazz Practice: Insights from Dave Pollack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pollack_advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 20:07:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pollack_advice/</guid>
      <description>Original YouTube Video&#xA;In a recent Q&amp;amp;A session, jazz musician Dave Pollack shared his expert advice on how to structure effective practice sessions. Whether you have a lot of time or just a few minutes, his tips can help you make the most of your practice. Here’s what he had to say:&#xA;Q: What should a regular practice session look like for jazz? Okay, so what I always recommend is breaking up (especially jazz practicing) into three parts:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
